A Guide to the Records of the Division of Motion Picture Censorship, 1926-1968
Library of Virginia
- Financial records, 1949-1965
  - Daily billing, 1963 January (Box 44, Folder 31)
  - Daily billing, 1963 February (Box 44, Folder 32)
  - Daily billing, 1963 March (Box 44, Folder 33)
  - Daily billing, 1963 April (Box 44, Folder 34)
  - Daily billing, 1963 May (Box 44, Folder 35)
  - Daily billing, 1963 June (Box 44, Folder 36)
  - Daily billing, 1963 July (Box 44, Folder 37)
  - Daily billing, 1963 August (Box 44, Folder 38)
  - Daily billing, 1963 September (Box 44, Folder 39)
  - Daily billing, 1963 October (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Daily billing, 1963 November (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Daily billing, 1963 December (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Daily billing, 1964 January (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Daily billing, 1964 February (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Daily billing, 1964 March (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Daily billing, 1964 April (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Daily billing, 1964 May (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Daily billing, 1964 June (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Daily billing, 1964 July (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Daily billing, 1964 August (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Daily billing, 1964 September (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Daily billing, 1964 October (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Daily billing, 1964 November (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Daily billing, 1964 December (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Daily billing, 1965 January (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Daily billing, 1965 February (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Daily billing, 1965 March (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Daily billing, 1965 April (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Daily billing, 1965 May (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - Daily billing, 1965 June-July (Box 45, Folder 21)
- Office Administrative Records, 1924-1966
  This series contains the office voucher files for the Division of Motion Picture Censorship. The files provide information on financial management as well as procedures for the operation and administration of the Division. There are also annual reports and attendance reports for the censors. Some topical files include information on the Commonwealth's personnel act, procurement procedures and monthly reports of monies collected by the Division. These records include a sampling of blank forms used by the Division during it's operation.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Additional funds, 1953 (Box 45, Folder 22)
  - Annual reports, 1924-1965 (Box 45, Folder 23)
  - Appropriations and classification codes, 1960 (Box 45, Folder 24)
  - Allotments and quarterly estimates, 1963-1965 (Box 45, Folder 25)
  - Attendance reports, 1948-1949 (Box 45, Folder 26)
  - Attendance reports, 1960-1965 (Box 45, Folder 27)
  - Audits, 1961-1965 (Box 45, Folder 28)
  - Authorized signatures, 1954-1958 (Box 45, Folder 29)
  - Budget, 1961-1964 (Box 45, Folder 30)
  - Budget, 1964-1966 (Box 45, Folder 31)
  - Budget, 1965-1966 (Box 45, Folder 32)
  - Disbursements, 1960-1966 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Employment reports, 1962-1966 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Expenditure statements, 1961-1966 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Financial statement, 1966 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Insurance, 1959-1966 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Invoice statements, 1961-1966 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Monthly reports of money collected, 1962-1966 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Monthly statements of revenue, 1961-1966 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Personnel Act (Virginia), 1942-1962 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Personnel Handbooks, 1958-1965 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Procurement guidelines, 1963-1966 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Purchase order statements, 1965-1966 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Receipts, 1961-1962 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Retirement manual, 1960-1964 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Salary Scale and Classifications, 1947-1966 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Sample forms, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 16)
- Reports of film clerks, 1960-1965
  This series consists of forms entitled Film Clerk's Report. This form consists of multiple pages with the following categories and headings: Title (movie title), Exchange (studio name), Number of Reel, Footage, Print Number, Original Seal Number, Duplicate Print Number, Duplicate Seal Number, and Substitute Seal. Not all categories on the form contain information.
  - Reports, 1960 July-August (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - Reports, 1960 September-October (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - Reports, 1960 November-December (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - Reports, 1961 January-March (Box 46, Folder 20)
  - Reports, 1961 April-May (Box 46, Folder 21)
  - Reports, 1961 June-July (Box 46, Folder 22)
  - Reports, 1961 August-September (Box 46, Folder 23)
  - Reports, 1961 October (Box 46, Folder 24)
  - Reports, 1961 November-December (Box 46, Folder 25)
  - Reports, 1962 January-February (Box 46, Folder 26)
  - Reports, 1962 March-April (Box 46, Folder 27)
  - Reports, 1962 May-June (Box 46, Folder 28)
  - Reports, 1962 July-August (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Reports, 1962 September-October (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Reports, 1962 November-December (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Reports, 1963 January-February (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Reports, 1963 March-April (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Reports, 1963 May-June (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Reports, 1963 July-August (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Reports, 1963 September-October (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Reports, 1963 November-December (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Reports, 1964 January-February (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Reports, 1964 March-April (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Reports, 1964 May-June (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Reports, 1964 July-August (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Reports, 1964 September-October (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Reports, 1964 November-December (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - Reports, 1965 January-February (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Reports, 1965 March (Box 48, Folder 2)
- Annual reports, 1924-1965
  This series contains the yearly reports for the Censorship Division as submitted to the Governor. The reports provide a detailed narrative and statistical breakdown of the activities for the fiscal year. The first report reflects in detail the standard used in the elimination and/or rejection of certain films. The main purpose for censorship was to prevent the display of "obscene, indecent, immoral or inhuman films of such character that their exhibition would tend to corrupt morals or incite crime."
  The earlier reports (roughly 1924-1935) offer a descriptive narrative acount of the activities of the Board. The reports of the 1920's document the improprieties of certain comic films of the day. One report states that "directors seem willing to violate all the refinements and all conventions in order to get a laugh." There are descriptions of total scenes cut from films along with examples given of specific movies and the reasons for the "slicing". The report for 1927-1928 highlights the advent of the new technology in motion pictures, "the talkies". Among the concerns of the Board about the new technology was the cost of purchasing new projectors that would allow viewing and editing of synchronized films. In the annual report of 1931 comments are made about the "great onslaught of gang pictures". This "problem" was not seen as vital for Virginia as for the "northern states where foreign population is greater". Nonetheless, the censors considered gangster movies fostered a "disagreeable situation" that members of the Division hoped producers of this genre of film would "tone down in the future".
  In the 1941 report advances in technology are highlighted with the introduction of a new projector known as the "Juke Box" that used sixteen millimeter film. Once again, the report documents concerns about getting state appropriations for the purchase of new equipment. The reports for 1943-1944 make note of the surprise in the increase in the number of films due to the fact of restrictions placed on raw materials (including film) during World War II.
  The reports for later years (roughly 1947-1965) are more statistical and less narrative in composition. The statistical tables give a numerical breakdown of films. The headings in the report include Totals for the Years, Elimination, Rejections, Receipts, Disbursements, and Revenue Refunds. The financial statements provide the amount of fees collected and turned over to the state treasurer. Often the statements will include disbursements of operating expenses and capital outlays.
  - Annual reports - bound and printed, 1924-1965 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Annual reports - original (typewritten), 1924-1965 (Box 48, Folder 4)
- Elimination records, 1945-1965
  This series consists of forms sent to the studios documenting in writing the eliminated scenes or cuts from feature films. The form contains the name and address of the studio, title of the movie, a brief and graphice description of the scene cut from the original movie, and the signatures of the Director of the Division of Motion Picture Censorship an the authorized agent for the studio. The form usually has triplicate copies and sometimes includes an attachment of correspondence between censors and studio executives.
  - Elimination records, 1945 October-1948 February (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Elimination records, 1949 October-1950 August (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Elimination records, 1951 June-1954 November (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Elimination records, 1955 January-1958 August (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Elimination records, 1958 June-1960 July (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Elimination records, 1961 July-1964 April (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Elimination records, 1964 April-1965 July (Box 48, Folder 11)
- Correspondence (Outgoing and Incoming), 1958-1966
  This series consists of carbon copies of letters mailed from the various director's of the Division of Motion Picture Censorship and the other censors. The letters cover a wide range of topics including the discussion with studio executives regarding censorship decisions made by the division. The files include information on the daily operations of the division along with the records from two prominent former directors, Mrs. Lollie C. Whitehead and Mrs. russell F. Wagers.
  - Correspondence - A, 1961-1964 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Annual reports (mailings), 1964-1965 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence - Attorney General, 1964-1966 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - B, 1962-1964 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - C, 1962-1965 (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence - Criticisms and comments, 1965-1966 (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence - D, 1963-1965 (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence - E, 1963-1964 (Box 48, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence - F, 1962-1964 (Box 48, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence - Film daily year book, 1964-1966 (Box 48, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence - G, 1962-1963 (Box 48, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence - Governor's file, 1965 (Box 48, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence - H, 1962-1965 (Box 48, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence - Heads of state agencies, 1965-1966 (Box 48, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence - I, 1962-1964 (Box 48, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence - J, 1961-1964 (Box 48, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence - K, 1960-1961 (Box 48, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence - L, 1963-1964 (Box 48, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence - Levine Enterprise, 1964-1965 (Box 48, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence - M, 1962-1964 (Box 48, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence - Maryland, 1963-1964 (Box 48, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence - N, 1961-1964 (Box 48, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence - Neighborhood Theaters, 1962-1964 (Box 48, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence - O, 1963 (Box 48, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence - Ontario, Toronto Canadian Film Censors, 1962-1963 (Box 48, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence - P, 1962-1965 (Box 48, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence - R, 1962-1963 (Box 48, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence - Requests for information on censorship, 1965-1966 (Box 48, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence - S, 1962-1965 (Box 48, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence - Safety (Governor's Highway), 1962-1963 (Box 48, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence - T, 1962-1965 (Box 48, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence - Telephone system, 1962-1965 (Box 48, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence - U, 1962-1963 (Box 48, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence - United Givers Fund, 1963-1965 (Box 48, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence - V, 1962-1963 (Box 48, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence - Virginia Supplemental Retirement, 1962-1965 (Box 48, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence - W, 1963-1965 (Box 48, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence - Wagers, Russell F., Mrs., 1958-1966 (Box 48, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence - Whitehead, Lollie C., Mrs., 1960-1965 (Box 48, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence - Y, 1964 (Box 48, Folder 51)
- Correspondence (Active Theaters and Drive-ins), 1957-1965
  This series consists of copies of outgoing and incoming letters between the Director of the Division of Motion Picture Censorship and theater and drive-in owners of viable theater within the state. The correspondence mainly conists of letters from the director seeking recommendations for the names of individuals to work as inspectors, to view films, and verify that the state seal had been appropriately applied to the print. The files are organized by the name of the theater and include the theater location. The files have special notations for "Negro" only theaters and inspectors. There are also report forms that list the number of admission cards issued to an inspector.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of theater.
  - Abingdon - Wicomico, Va., 1961-1965 (Box 48, Folder 52)
  - Afton - Cradock, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 48, Folder 53)
  - Airport - Galax and Sandston, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 48, Folder 54)
  - American - Roanoke, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 48, Folder 55)
  - Amherst - Madison Heights, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 48, Folder 56)
  - Anchor - Newport News, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 48, Folder 57)
  - Arlington - Arlington, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Ashland - Ashland, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - AutoDrone, Radford, Va. 1961-1965 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Autoport - Portsmouth, Va., 1962-1965 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Barracks Road - Charlottesville, Va., 1964-1965 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Bayne - Virginia Beach, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - B and L - Williamsburg, Va., 1964-1965 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Beach Theater - Virginia Beach, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Beacon - Hopewell, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Bedford - Bedford, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Bellwood - Richmond, Va., 1961-1965 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Bluebird - Petersburg, Va., 1958-1965 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Bluegrass - Castlewood, Va., 1960-1964 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Blue Star - Petersburg, Va., 1959-1964 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Boulevard - Norfolk, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Bradlick - Annandale, Va., 1964-1965 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Broadway - Richmond, Va., 1961-1965 (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Buchanan - Buchanan, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - Buckingham - Arlington, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 19)
  - Buena Vista - Buena Vista, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 20)
  - Byrd - Arlington, Va., 1961-1965 (Box 49, Folder 21)
  - Byrd - Norfolk, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 22)
  - Cameo - Bristol, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 23)
  - Capitol - Danville, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 24)
  - Capitol - Portsmouth, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 25)
  - Caroline - Bowling Green, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 26)
  - Carrsville - Carrsville, Va., 1960-1964 (Box 49, Folder 27)
  - Carver - Norfolk, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 28)
  - Castle - Martinsville, Va., 1960-1963 (Box 49, Folder 29)
  - Cavalier - Waynesboro, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 30)
  - Cavalier - Elkton, Va., 1961-1964 (Box 49, Folder 31)
  - Cavalier - Lebanon, Va., 1960-1964 (Box 49, Folder 32)
  - Central - Blackwood, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 33)
  - Centre - Alexandria, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 34)
  - Century - Petersburg, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 35)
  - Chatham - Chatham, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 36)
  - Circle - Richmond, Va., 1960-1964 (Box 49, Folder 37)
  - Clinch - Tazewell, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 38)
  - Coeburn - Coeburn, Va., 1961-1965 (Box 49, Folder 39)
  - Colley - Norfolk, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 40)
  - Colonial - Fredericksburg, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 41)
  - Colonial - Norfolk, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 42)
  - Colonial - South Hill, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 43)
  - Colony - Portsmouth, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 44)
  - Commodore - Portsmouth, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 45)
  - Community - Woodstock, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 46)
  - Coswell - Appomattox, Va., 1961-1965 (Box 49, Folder 47)
  - Covington - Covington, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 48)
  - Craig - Craigsville, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 49)
  - Cresent - Danville, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 50)
  - Dante - Dante, Va., 1960-1964 (Box 49, Folder 51)
  - Dalton - Pulaski, Va., 1962-1964 (Box 49, Folder 52)
  - Daw - Tappahannock, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 53)
  - Dick's - Cumberland, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 54)
  - Dick's - Louisa, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 55)
  - Dixie - Newport News, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 56)
  - Dixie - Staunton, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 57)
  - Dixie - Vinton, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 58)
  - Donk's - Hudgins, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 59)
  - Dunbar - Norfok, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 60)
  - Elkton - Elkton, Va., 1960-1964 (Box 49, Folder 61)
  - Emporia - Emporia, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 62)
  - Ewing - Ewing, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 63)
  - Fairfax - Fairfax, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 64)
  - Fairfax - Kilmarnock, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 65)
  - Fairfield - Richmond, Va., 1961-1965 (Box 49, Folder 66)
  - Family - Martinsville, Va., 1960-1964 (Box 49, Folder 67)
  - Family - Stephens City, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 68)
  - Farmville - Farmville, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 69)
  - Fauquier - Warrenton, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 70)
  - 501 Drive-In - South Boston, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 71)
  - Flanary - Richlands, Va., 1960-1964 (Box 49, Folder 72)
  - Fork Union - Fork Union, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 73)
  - Fox Drive - Onley, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 74)
  - Free State - Kenbridge, Va., 1961-1965 (Box 49, Folder 75)
  - Gem Theater - Petersburg, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 76)
  - Giles - Rich Creek, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 77)
  - Glebe - Arlington, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 78)
  - Golden Gate - Amelia, Va., 1960-1964 (Box 49, Folder 79)
  - Glen Drive - Richmond, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 80)
  - Gordonsville - Gordonsville, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 81)
  - Granby - Norfolk, Va., 1960-1964 (Box 49, Folder 82)
  - Grand Theater - Norfolk, Va., 1960-1964 (Box 49, Folder 83)
  - Grandin - Roanoke, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 84)
  - Green Acres - Hampton, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 49, Folder 85)
  - Grove - Blackstone, Va., 1961-1965 (Box 49, Folder 86)
  - Guy's - Richlands, Va., 1961-1964 (Box 49, Folder 87)
  - Hable's Palace - Winchester, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Halifax Theater - South Bostson, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Harrisonburg - Harrisonburg, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Harvey's Drive-In - Lynchburg, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Hester Drive-In - Fries, Va., 1961-1964 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Highland - Bluegrass, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Highland - Rural Retreat, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Hillsdale - Washington, Va., 1959-1964 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Hillsville - Hillsville, Va., 1960-1964 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Hi-Way - New Market, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Hi-Way - Craigsville, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Hi-Way - Radford, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Home Theater - Strasburg, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Homestead - Hot Springs, Va., 1961-1965 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Hull - Lexington, Va., 1960-1964 (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Idle Hour - Belle Haven, Va., 1960-1964 (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - Island - Chincoteague, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 17)
  - James - Newport News, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - Jefferson - Charlottesville, Va., 1959-1964 (Box 50, Folder 19)
  - Jefferson - Falls Church, Va., 1961-1965 (Box 50, Folder 20)
  - Jefferson - Newport News, Va. (Negro), 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 21)
  - Jefferson - Roanoke, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 22)
  - Keysville - Keysville, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 23)
  - King's Palace - Alexandria, Va. (Negro), 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 24)
  - Koltown - Norton, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 25)
  - Langley - Hampton, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 26)
  - Laurel - Damascus, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 27)
  - Lee - Pennington Gap, Va., 1960-1964 (Box 50, Folder 28)
  - Lee - Roanoke, Va., 1961-1965 (Box 50, Folder 29)
  - Lee Highway Drive-In - Merrifield, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 30)
  - Lee Hi Drive-In, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 31)
  - Lenox - Norfolk, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 32)
  - Liberty - Hot Springs, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 33)
  - Lincoln - Marion, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 34)
  - Lowe's State - Norfolk, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 35)
  - Lynn - New Castle, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 36)
  - Lynwood - Grandy, Va., 1961-1965 (Box 50, Folder 37)
  - Lyon - Waverly, Va., 1961-1965 (Box 50, Folder 38)
  - Lyon State Theater - Franklin, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 39)
  - Lyric - Blacksburg, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 40)
  - Lyric - Lexington, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 41)
  - Lyric - St. Paul, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 42)
  - Martin Theater - Martinsville, Va., 1960-1963 (Box 50, Folder 43)
  - Martinsville Drive-In - Martinsville, Va., 1960-1962 (Box 50, Folder 44)
  - Masonic - Clifton Forge, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 45)
  - Mayfair - Colonial Beach, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 46)
  - Memrose - Norfolk, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 47)
  - Messick - Poquoson, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 48)
  - Millwald - Wytheville, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 49)
  - Moonlight - Abingdon, Va., 1959-1965 (Box 50, Folder 50)
  - Moorcones - Purcelville, Va., 1960-1964 (Box 50, Folder 51)
  - Morgan - Grundy, Va., 1960-1964 (Box 50, Folder 52)
  - Moton - Newport News, Va. (Negro), 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 53)
  - Mount Theater - Rocky Mount, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 54)
  - Mount Joy - Buchanan, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 55)
  - Mount Vernon - Alexandria, Va., 1961-1965 (Box 50, Folder 56)
  - Mullin - Clintwood, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 57)
  - Nelson - Lovingston, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 58)
  - Newport Theater - Norfolk, Va., 1957-1965 (Box 50, Folder 59)
  - New Raven - Raven, Va., 1960-1964 (Box 50, Folder 60)
  - Norfolk Drive-In - Norfolk, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 61)
  - North 11 Drive-In - Roanoke, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 62)
  - North 340 Drive-In - Waynesboro, Va., 1960-1964 (Box 50, Folder 63)
  - Norva Theater - Norfolk, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 64)
  - Nottoway - Blackstone, Va., 1960-1964 (Box 50, Folder 65)
  - Oak Theater - South Hill, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 66)
  - Page - Luray, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 67)
  - Page Drive-In - Luray, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 68)
  - Palace - Christiansburg, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 69)
  - Palace - Newport News, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 70)
  - Palace - Suffolk, Va., 1960-1964 (Box 50, Folder 71)
  - Paramount - Charlottesville, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 72)
  - Paramount - Lynchburg, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 73)
  - Paramount - Newport News, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 74)
  - Park Drive-In - Marion, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 75)
  - Park Drive-In - Petersburg, Va., 1961-1965 (Box 50, Folder 76)
  - Park Drive-In - Pearisburg, Va., 1961-1965 (Box 50, Folder 77)
  - Patrick Drive-In - Patrick Springs, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 78)
  - Pearis Theater - Peasrisburg, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 79)
  - Pitts Theater - Culpeper, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 80)
  - Pitts Drive-In - Culpeper, Va., 1960-1965 (Box 50, Folder 81)